These subtitles are not for distribution on for-profit streaming websites. The operators of these websites are pulling a profit from the hard work of fansubbers, and the anime creators themselves.
https://kumo8.github.io/GanbatteSubs/
These people are probably all around you.
No matter how hard you try, you can never match them.
People you can't help but look at with envy and jealousy.
They have no flaws...
They are leaders, entrepreneurs, stars...
Known as geniuses, they leave their mark on history.
But are they really perfect?
No, not at all.
They have something secret...
Something they would never tell anyone...
Something that leads them to success...
Something we call...
Aguu.
What on earth is this manga?
Is this even a manga?
It's only exposition. Where's the main character?
What a strange book.
Excuse me.
Could you take your legs off the shelves please?
Huh?
S-sorry sorry sorry sorry....
My name is Ai.
I like manga and hot guys.
I'm a normal 16 year-old girl.
Any time, any place, I'll absent-mindedly do the splits.
It will often surprise those around me, though....
It's my habit.
It's because I'm a professional ballet dancer.
Well...
I have absolutely no chance of reaching prima ballerina.
The thing that got me into ballet,
was a girl I met in ballet class.
We always trained together,
and quickly became close friends.
But before I knew it, a large gap developed between us.
Her talent bloomed into genius that anyone might envy.
But I was left struggling to improve, as always.
Though, thankfully, we remained friends.
Her name is Machi.
I wanted to become like her and put my heart into my practice.
I am... probably not a prodigy.
But I believe that if I work hard, it will someday pay off.
I'm done. I'm too tired.
Machi, what about practice?
You were up all night again, weren't you?
I suppose.
Hey.
I've got some bad news.
You want to hear?
I know. The Heroine Audition tomorrow.
You've basically got the position already.
I'll still give it my best though.
No, not that. It's your boyfriend.
He asked me out yesterday.
He only started going out with you to get close to me.
What an absolute lowlife.
I gave him a good slap.
I'm done.
I'll go home.
Practice is good....
But don't overdo it.
There's no point if you hurt yourself now.
Machi!
Uhm...
Thank you.
Of course.
We're friends.
Everything I long for, Machi always attains it so easily.
Why are we so different?
But... but, this is exactly the reason why.
I need to practice a whole lot harder.
Someday, I will be like Machi,
I'll stand on the stage as a prima ballerina.
From time to time I'll feel envious, and a little resentful.
I don't want to be that sort of person.
Wow. At the level I'm at right now,
I don't think I'm even a match for these people.
I mean, they are all doing the same dance,
yet they look like they are having so much fun.
Oi, stop.
I said stop!
How persistent. You were still here?
Go home. You're in the way of our dancing.
No way! This is a public place.
If you old fossils can dance, why do we have to sell books?
Watch your mouth! Who's an old fossil?
I'm a young woman.
I know an old fossil when I see one.
This is enough. Rafu, stop it,
But Gramps, surely we can't just let them do as they please.
This is our place.
Though if you were to insist...
We'll take this gentleman.
There aren't any men in our group, you know.
- Ooh, how nice.
- Wonderful.
- Yes, let's get this one.
Don't be ridiculous. Gramps' gotta sell these books.
He can't dance!
Well then get out of the way!
T-that book, that's the one I read in the bookshop this morning, right?
Rafu, let's go somewhere else.
We're causing a nuisance.
But Gramps...
Hey kid, you should listen to your Grandpa.
Yeah I know.
If it's gonna be like this, I'll dance.
What?
I said I'll dance with you instead of Gramps.
But while I'm dancing with you, you've got to
leave Gramps alone and let him sell books here.
Are you sure?
It's fine.
- You'll dance?
- Isn't he too young?
- He's not the type.
Shut up!
Anyway, we're in the way of Gramps here. Follow me.
Let me help.
Sorry for the trouble.
Not at all.
But this is pretty rough, though.
Having to sell such a strange book....
I mean, I can't understand what's written in it at all.
I'd like something more exciting.
Some adventure, or passion...
You read this book?
Yeah, a little bit at the bookshop.
Really? Thank you.
"Thank you"?
I wrote this book.
Sorry sorry sorry sorry....
It's fine. But you know...
I have no intention of writing common fiction.
Everything in this book is the absolute truth.
A description of truth inside the real world.
The truth?
I'll give you a copy. Take it home with you.
O-oh I couldn't possibly.
It's no trouble. Consider it thanks for helping me out.
Thank you very much.
If you read this to the end, you will understand.
You will see that there's something you don't have.
Something I don't have?
Aguu.
Aguu?
Those of us who don't have an aguu
are without a doubt, on the losing side.
Who's there?
Ai, the bath is free.
What's wrong? You look like you've seen a ghost.
M-man.
(Translator's note: Man is the person's name)
Don't scare me like that.
I was just letting you know.
So, what about the bath?
I'll take one tomorrow.
You sure? The audition is tomorrow morning.
Yeah.
Well, I suppose it's fine if you're late.
It'll be one less rival.
Hey!
See ya later. Good night.
Honestly...
That old man was talking about "the truth".
I really don't get it.
Aguu glasses?
"These glasses allow one to see the aguu that geniuses have".
"Effective within 30 minutes of removal".
The thing that geniuses have?
Stop.
What's your name?
Ai.
The fundamentals are strong, but...
I feel like the expressiveness is lacking.
Okay, Next! Machi!
Yes.
Thank you.
Thank you for this opportunity.
Something I don't have.
Something only geniuses have.
I wonder if Machi has it, that thing.
What's this? Nothing has changed.
Neither the director or manager have changed.
The other students haven't changed either.
Well, of course. I'm so foolish.
How could I take this book seriously?
Sorry, Machi.
Anyway, 32 perfectly executed whipped turns...
Machi is in perfect form today.
I feel a rush of excitement as she dances.
It keeps getting more beautiful and beautiful.
Machi is, truly, a genius.
What was that on her wrist? Thread?
No, not just her wrist.
It's tied to her shoulders and her neck.
Her back, waist, knees, ankles, feet...
There's thread coming from her whole body.
Where is this connected to?
What is that?
No way? Is that... aguu?
Machi is using aguu?
Everything in this book is the absolute truth.
If you read this to the end, you will understand.
You will see that there's something you don't have.
Aguu.
I don't believe it. It was so busy yesterday.
Where is that old man?
Oi!
You finally turned up.
You're late.
I thought you'd turn up.
You're, the one from yesterday...
Just be quiet and follow me.
Gramps is waiting.
I see.
Please tell me.
Was that aguu?
Aguu glasses make the powers emitted by the aguu visible.
That you saw what you did,
means that your friend is borrowing the power of the aguu.
May I ask a question?
Did the faces of any of the three aguu you saw seem familiar to you?
For example, did any resemble a genius ballet dancer
who, in the past, might have suddenly disappeared?
A genius ballet dancer?
Now that you mention it...
One looked like Helen, an 18th century British ballet dancer.
Another one seemed to resemble the 17th century Russian ballet genius, Nastasia.
And the last one looked awfully similar to the present-day Japanese ballet genius, Nagasawa Nami.
The first two disappeared at the height of their popularity.
Nagasawa committed suicide.
They didn't disappear or commit suicide.
They were taken captive.
Taken captive?
Yes. Taken captive, and made into aguu.
Subject to the utmost of cruel procedures.
The true geniuses, loved and selected by the gods, are each accompanied by a guardian spirit.
When a genius is born, so is the spirit.
When a genius dies, so too does the spirit.
However, back in the middle ages,
a group invented a wicked procedure
that binds a guardian spirit and allowed them to use its power.
They called themselves "The Tailors".
Once they abducted a genius, they would
carve magic wards all over their body to stave off death,
break their bones, and drain their blood.
They kept their captive alive,
while shrinking them down to the size of a child's fist.
Finally, they would bind up their captive's
hands, feet, and mouth with needle and thread.
And so, using this wicked technique,
a cursed doll–an aguu–is complete.
The aguu suffer on for eternity,
zombie-like, unable to ever die.
Why.... why would someone do such a horrible thing?
Because someone wanted it, obviously.
The power of the guardian spirit.
If you have an aguu you have the power of the guardian spirit.
Any loser can become a genius by sewing an aguu into their body.
This is the same for your friend.
Even Machi?
Using one is dangerous enough. But using three?
Your friend is a right piece of shit.
Stop. Don't talk about my friend that way.
It's true!
Three people who did nothing wrong are suffering inside her body,
and you don't care.
Machi might not know that!
No way she doesn't know.
She would see when she sewed the aguu into her body.
The suffering aguu.
Please stop, Rafu.
I don't believe you. Machi has always been so nice.
Nice? Anyone who uses aguu is scum.
Machi isn't scum.
I know scum when I see it.
Stop!
Sorry for shouting.
Rafu, please stop being rude.
Miss, I have a request.
I wonder if you would hear me out.
A request?
We want to save those three aguu you saw.
You can do that?
We can.
Who, exactly, are you?
Saviours.
We work to release the poor aguu from eternal suffering.
Saviours?
Releasing all the aguu is our mission as saviours.
I cannot overlook the aguu before me.
Will you help us save those three, miss?